Hey friends, welcome to you. How to file an insurance claim online
if your motorcycle meets with an accident. Let's
learn this.
Look at the screen, I have created a
slideshow. It has all the details. You
can take a screenshot if you want.
What is the first step?
First, you have to approach the insurance
company within
7 days. If you are not filing the claim within 7 days, you
can do it even after that, but its procedure is a little different.
I will explain it at the end of the video.
After that, in the second step, you approach the
service center and tell them
how the accident happened with your bike and
what parts are damaged. And the third
step is where you have some of your
documents which you will have to give to the service center,
like you should have an insurance policy, maybe an
Aadhar card. It will be
there. A
budget estimate of the parts will be made as to
how much it will cost. Okay,
after that, let's go to the sex tape.
In this, you have to fill up the information that the insurance company will give you. It will contain
all the details like your biodata etc.
and where your accident happened. These are all the
details which you have.  You can easily fill it, the
parts statement that has been made for you will
first be checked whether it is available in the service center
or not and the parts that are available will be given
to the service center, then this demand will be placed, then the
parts will come, only then it is
possible that there will be
pass parts on your bike, okay let's
move on after this, the
owner of the bike has to verify himself
that my bike is fitted properly and
is in good condition now and we come to the final step,
if you are insuring yourself, that
means I am talking about the bike owner himself, if you are
answering that my bike is
fine, then you will tell the insurance company
that I have to give my bike to
them in good condition, that is
fine but what happened in my case,
my service center does not have cashless transaction, so that is why
they
deposited the payment in my account, I deposited it in my account
and then I paid it to the service center,
but in
this case, in my case, the entire payment
came to me, they are not making me pay any extra post,
but if you give the insurance
claim
to the service center, then
you will have to pay 10% there.
Maybe we have to pay, then there is no need to be a daily for this
and last time what I
told you was that
if you cannot complain
to the insurance company for any reason, then they
ask for a delay certificate in which you can write
in the language of your state Hindi or English,
so there is no big deal in that, the
insurance company does it on its own, the
insurance company
plays the best role here and they will explain this work to you very
well and they will give 100% from their side,
you should stay away from the service center
because when the parts are fitted
in the bike, then you should be present there,
if you are not present then later
when you go for inspection or go to check yourself at the
time of fitting, then sit
comfortably and see whether it is taking 12 kilometers or
not and then declare the
bike ok,
thank you for the insurance claim